<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Case of the booksellers and printers, relating to the patentees for the sole printing all books of the Common-Law.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B18631</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886133</idno>
  <idno type="VID">186022</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240895000</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing C1016A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide T.100*[54]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R225500</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886133</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886133e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B18631)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 186022)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C3:2[53])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Case of the booksellers and printers, relating to the patentees for the sole printing all books of the Common-Law.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1669?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>With a docket title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Printing --  England --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Restraint of trade --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Monopolies --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="appeal">
            <pb facs="tcp:186022:1"/>
            <head>THE CASE OF THE Booksellers and Printers, Relating to the PATENTEES for the sole Printing all <hi>Books</hi> of the <hi>Common-Law.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THAT for some Years last past, several private Persons, for their own particular Gain, have procured <hi>Patents</hi> for the sole printing all Books whatsoever, relating to the common <hi>Law</hi> of this Land. And as such Patentees are not <hi>Printers</hi> by Trade, but Gentlemen, they Farm out the same to others, which Practices are attended with very great Inconveniencies, and are the Occasion of great <hi>Oppressions</hi> upon the Printers and Booksellers, as well as the rest of Her Majesties <hi>Subjects.</hi> For,</p>
            <p n="1">I. Such Patents are conceived to be a <hi>Monopoly,</hi> a thing very odious in the Eye of the <hi>Law,</hi> and have been once adjudged to be so by all the <hi>Iudges.</hi> For as it would be a Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nopoly, should the Crown grant to any one Person, or Body of Men, the sole Priviledge of making of <hi>Cards,</hi> which is a kind of printing: Why should a Printer be under any <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>straint</hi> from exercising so considerable a Branch of his Trade, as that of printing <hi>Law-Books</hi> is? Or why should any Man who hath a mind to publish a Treatise of Law, be forced to have it printed at the <hi>Patentees-Press,</hi> and not be at his <hi>liberty</hi> to have it done where he can have it done best and cheapest?</p>
            <p n="2">II. This is the Occasion of the common Complaint of the excessive Price of all Books re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating to the Law. For the <hi>Booksellers</hi> being forced to print all such Books at the Press of the <hi>Patentees,</hi> they compel them to pay five or six Shillings <hi>per</hi> Pound <hi>more</hi> than the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Price of printing any where else. Besides, they are as long again in the printing of the <hi>Law-Books,</hi> as any other Printers are in doing of the same Work.</p>
            <p n="3">III. That the first Pretensions of granting such Patents now <hi>ceases.</hi> For when Reporters of the Law were appointed and paid by the <hi>Crown,</hi> the Crown had an Interest in their <hi>Works,</hi> and it was very reasonable it should appoint who should be the <hi>Printers</hi> and Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lishers of 'em. But since that Usage is no longer practised, but every Man is at <hi>liberty</hi> to write what Treatises of <hi>Law</hi> he pleases. 'Tis unreasonable, that when a <hi>Bookseller</hi> hath given an Author 2 or 300 <hi>l.</hi> for a <hi>Copy,</hi> he should be forced to pay near half as much more to the Patentees, for <hi>Liberty</hi> to publish it to the World.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. That when such Patents were first granted, the Books of the Law were very <hi>few,</hi> and the <hi>Books</hi> in which the <hi>Crown</hi> might be conceived to have any <hi>Interest,</hi> were men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned therein, and the <hi>Patent</hi> was granted for such <hi>Books.</hi> Besides, the Number of <hi>Presses</hi> were then very <hi>small;</hi> but since Printing-Houses are <hi>increased,</hi> there being about 70 now in <hi>London,</hi> and the Books of the Law, as well as Printers, are grown very nume<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous; It can't be thought hard to say, that such Patents are, at least, a great <hi>Prejudice</hi> to the Improvement of Knowledge, the useful Art of PRINTING, and the Trade of those who have no other Method to get a Living.</p>
            <p n="5">V. That the <hi>Crown</hi> hath no manner of <hi>Advantage</hi> by such Patents, but the Usage of them may be very <hi>dangerous,</hi> for if such Patents should be allowed, it may seem as reason<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to grant a Patent to a Man, for the sole <hi>Binding</hi> of all Law-Books. For Printing is as much a Trade as Book-binding.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Wherefore it is humbly hoped, That this Honourable House will be pleased to take their</hi> CASE <hi>into Consideration, and to give them such Relief herein, as to your great Wisdom shall think most just and reasonable.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="docket_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:186022:2"/>
            <p>THE CASE OF THE <hi>Booksellers</hi> and <hi>Pri<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ters,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Relating to the <hi>Patentee<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> for the sole Printing all <hi>Books</hi> of the <hi>Common-Law.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>